Guide to the Robert Hofstadter Papers SC0426
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Robert Hofstadter papers
1931-1993
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Hofstadter, Robert
SC0426
83.75 Linear Feet (66 boxes)
This collection contains the papers of former Stanford professor and Nobel Prize winning physicist Robert Hofstadter. Included are lab notebooks and research data; lecture notes and teaching materials; writings, drafts, and reprints; grant proposals; incoming and outgoing correspondence; travel and conference papers; legal papers; biographical and personal materials;clippings; photographs; and a small amount of audiovisual material. The papers cover a wide swath of Hofstadter's career, including his student and postgraduate work at Princeton University; wartime positions at The United States National Bureau of Standards and Norden Laboratory; Stanford research including electron scattering and coronary angiography; and his collaboration with NASA personnel on the Energetic Gamma-Ray Experiment Telescope (EGRET).
Arrangement
The papers are arranged in four accessions, mirroring how the collection was received. One additional catagory, Oversized Items, was created during processing and consists of large items removed from elsewhere in the collection. Whenever possible, the contents of the collection were left in the order in which they were received.
The 2005, 2008, and 2011 accessions each contain several subcategories, which are listed alphabetically within each accession. These categories, most of which repeat across accessions, include awards and honors; biographical materials; clippings; correspondence, KMS Fusion; lecture notes and teaching materials; research; photographs; publications and writings; speeches and presentations; and travel and conferences. The 2008 accession also includes a subcategory of Hofstadter's research files and writings on colleague Felix Bloch.
Robert Hofstadter's son, Douglas, provided numerous notes on the contents of folders within the collection. These notes were kept with the folders to which they pertain and are noted in the collection inventory.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The papers were a gift of the family of Robert Hofstadter, 1992, 1995, 2008, and 2011.
Information about Access
Letters of recommendation in Accession 1995-014 and Accession 2008-003 are restricted. Otherwise the collection is open for research. The collection is stored off site; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Robert (Rubvin) Hofstadter was born in New York City, on February 5, 1915. He was one of four children of Polish immigrants, Louis and Henrietta (Koenigsberg) Hofstadter. Hofstadter was educated in New York City and attended the City College of New York (CCNY) receiving his B.S. degree magna cum laude.
Hofstadter attended graduate school at Princeton University and received both M.A. and Ph.D. degrees in physics in 1938 His Ph.D. work was concerned with infrared spectra of simple organic molecules, and in particular, with the structure of the hydrogen bond. From 1938-1939, he held a Procter Fellowship at Princeton for postdoctoral work, during which he began a study of photoconductivity in willemite crystals. In 1939, Hofstadter received the Harrison Fellowship at the University of Pennsylvania, where he helped to construct a large Van de Graaff machine for nuclear research.
During World War II Hofstadter worked at the National Bureau of Standards and the Norden Laboratory Corporation. After the war, he returned to Princeton as Assistant Professor of Physics, where he researched crystal conduction counters, the Compton effect, and scintillation counters.
In 1950, with the encouragement of colleagues Leonard Schiff and Felix Bloch, Hofstadter left Princeton to become Associate Professor of Physics at Stanford University, where he began research on electron scattering with a linear accelerator. While building equipment for the electron-scattering experiments, he continued working on scintillation counters and developed new detectors for neutrons and X-rays. Other research conducted during Hofstadter’s early years at Stanford concerned cosmic rays and with cascade showers generated by high-speed electrons.
Hofstadter was elected to the National Academy of Sciences in 1958 and was named California Scientist of the Year in 1959. In 1961, he received the Nobel Prize in Physics based on his electron scattering studies of the nucleon.
From 1967-1974, Hofstadter directed the High Energy Physics Laboratory at Stanford. He went on to collaborate with colleagues at Stanford’s School of Medicine in the development of synchrotron radiation and K-edge subtraction for coronary angiography (a diagnostic technique which uses radioactive substances in place of catheters to test heart function). In his later years he worked with NASA physicists and technicians to design the Energetic Gamma-Ray Experimental Telescope (EGRET), which was one of four instruments equipped for the Compton Gamma-Ray Observatory Satellite.
Hofstadter passed away in November of 1990, just prior to EGRET’s launch in 1991. His contributions were commemorated with a plaque that was attached to the observatory.
Hofstadter married Nancy Givan of Baltimore, Maryland in 1942. They were the parents of one son, Douglas, and two daughters, Laura and Molly.
Description of the Collection
This collection contains the papers of former Stanford professor and Nobel Prize winning physicist Robert Hofstadter. Included are lab notebooks and research data; and related files; lecture notes and teaching materials; writings, drafts, and reprints; grant proposals; incoming and outgoing correspondence; travel and conference papers; legal papers; biographical and personal materials; clippings; photographs; and a small amount of audiovisual material. The papers cover a wide swath of Hofstadter's career, including his student and postgraduate work at Princeton University; wartime positions at The United States National Bureau of Standards and Norden Laboratory; Stanford research including electron scattering and coronary angiography; and his collaboration with NASA personnel on the Energetic Gamma-Ray Experiment Telescope. Of particular interest are materials on the development of the Stanford Linear Accelerator Center (SLAC), later renamed the SLAC National Accelerator Laboratory, as well as correspondence on the relationship between SLAC and the Stanford University Department of Phyiscs.
Particles (Nuclear physics); Gamma rays; Physics -- Research.; Linear accelerators; Form factor (Nuclear physics); Laser fusion; Pulsars -- Detection; Electrons -- Scattering; Physics.; Physics -- Study and teaching.; Scattering (Physics); Angiography; Muons; Nobel Prize winners; United States. National Bureau of Standards; Chodorow, Marvin; Hansen, W. W. (William Webster); Norden Laboratory Corporation; Bloch, Felix; United States. National Aeronautics and Space Administration; Schawlow, Arthur L.; Hofstadter, Robert; Panofsky, Wolfgang K.H. (Wolfgang Kurt Hermann); Stanford Linear Accelerator Center; European Organization for Nuclear Research; Stanford University. Department of Physics. Faculty; Harshaw Chemical Company; Stanford University. W.W. Hansen Laboratories of Physics. High Energy Physics Laboratory; Hofstadter, Robert; Hofstadter, Douglas R.; Kaplan, Henry S.; Goddard Space Flight Center; Ginzton, Edward L. (Edward Leonard); KMS Fusion, Inc.; Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory
- Papers, Accession ARCH-1992-097
  Scope and Contents
  This accession consists of papers authored by Robert Hofstadter. The papers were retained in the order in which they were received; the original numbering scheme was also retained. A number of empty folders were discovered during processing and are noted in the inventory. They have been retained to preserve the integrity of the original numbering scheme. Researchers should note that much overlap exists between this series and the Publications subseries found elsewhere in the collection.
  - "The Infrared Absorption Spectrum of Formic Acid Vapor," Physical Review, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "The Infrared Absorption Spectra and Approximate Force of Propene and Allene," Physical Review, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "Infrared Absorption Spectra of Light and Heavy Acetic Acids", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - "Absorption Spectra of Heavy formic Acid," Phyiscal Review (empty folder), 1938 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Infrared Absorption Spectrum of Heavy Acetic Acids", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - "Vibration Spectra and Molecular Structure IV. -- The infrared absorption spectra of the double and single molecules of formic acid," (includes copies of article from various publications, including Journal of American Physics), 1938 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - "Vibration Spectra and Molecular Structure V. -- red studies on light and heavy acetic acids," (empty folder), 1938 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "Vibration Spectra and Molecular Structure VI. -- red absorption spectrum of heavy formic acids", 1938 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Photoconductivity in Willemite" (letter to editor), 1938 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - "Further Studies on the Infrared Absorption Spectra of the Fatty Acids," Physical Review, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - "The Infrared Absorption Spectrum of Phenol Vapor," Physical Review, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - "Photoconductivity of Crystalline Willemite at Low Temperatures," Physical Review, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - "Vibration Spectra and Molecular Structure VII. -- further infrared studies on the vapors of some carboxylic acids" (empty folder), 1939 Jul (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - "Vibration Spectra and Molecular Structure VIII. -- absorption spectra of light and heavy phenol and aniline vapors" (empty folder), 1939 Sep (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - "Observations on the Dark Current of a Willemite Crystal," Physical Review, 1940 May 15 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - "Photoconductivity of a Natural Willemite Crystal," Physical Review, 1941 Jan 1 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - "Peak and Null Indicating Circuit", 1941 Sep (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - "A Tube for the Franck-Hertz Experiment," American Journal of Physics, 1942 Apr (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - "Mechanical-Electronic Control Systems," Physical Review, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - "A Simple Potentiometer Circuit for Production of the Tangent Function" (empty folder), 1946 Aug (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Rate-of-Change," Electronics, 1947 May (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - "Use of Silver Chloride at Low Temperatures as Counters", 1947 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Behavior of Silver Chloride Crystal Counters," Physical Review, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - "Thallium Halide Crystal Counter," Physical Review, 1947 Dec (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - "Remarks on Diamond Crystal Counters" (empty folder), 1948 Mar (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Alkali Halide Scintillation Counters" (empry folder), 1948 Jul (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - "Detection of Neutrons with Scintillation Counters", 1948 Nov (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - "Temperature Dependence of Scintillations in Sodium Iodide Crystals", 1949 Jan (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - "The Detection of Gamma-Rays with Thallium Activated Sodium Iodide Crystals" (with erratum), 1949 Mar (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - "Luminescent Spectra of Phosphors Useful in Scintillation Counters," Physical Review, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - "Pulse Size Distribution in Scintillation Counters," Physical Review (empty folder), undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - "Simultaneity in the Compton Effect," American Physical Society, 1950 Apr (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "Experimental Study of the Compton Effect at 1.2 MeV", 1949 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - "Crystal Counters", 1949 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - "Scintillation Counters," ONR Research Review, 1949 Sep (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - "Note on the Detection of Coincidences and Short Time Intervals," Review of Scientific Instruments, 1950 Jan (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - "Simultaneity in the Compton Effect" (empty folder), 1950 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - "Terphenyl and Dibenzyl Scintillation Counters," Physical Review, 1950 Feb (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - "Measurement of Gamma-Ray Energies with One Crystal," Physical Review, 1950 Jun (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "Measurement of Gamma-Ray Energies with Two Crystals in Coincidence," Physical Review, 1950 Jun (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - "Crystal Counters," I.R.E., 1950 Jul (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - "Gamma-Ray Measurements with NaI(Tl) Crystals," Physical Review (includes draft), 1950 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - "Research on Crystal Detection of Ionizing Radiation", 1950 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - "Gamma-Ray Spectroscopy with Crystals of NaI(Tl)", 1950 Sep (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - "Measurement of Gamma-Ray Energies with Crystals of NaI(Tl)," Physical Review, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - "The Measurement of Gamma-Ray Energies with Single Crystals of NaI(Tl)," Physical Review, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - "Detection of X-Rays by Means of NaI(Tl) Scintillation Counters," Physical Review, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - "Detection of Slow Neutrons," Physical Review, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - "Scintillation in Thallium-Activated CaI2 and CsI" (empty folder), 1951 Dec (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - "Energy Loss of Cosmic Ray u-Mesons," Physical Review (empty folder), 1952 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - "Gamma- and Alpha- Produced Scintillations in Cesium Fluoride," Physical Review, 1952 Jun (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - "Energy Loss of Cosmic-Ray MU-Mesons in Sodium Iodide Crystals" (empty folder), 1952 Jun (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - "Electron-Induced Showers in Copper," Physical Review, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - "Scattering of High-Energy Electrons and the Method of Nuclear Recoil," Physical Review, also HEPL no. 105, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - "Electron Scattering from Nuclei at High Energies," Physical Review, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - "Electron-Induced Showers," Physical Review, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - "High Energy Electron Scattering and Nuclear Structure Determinations," HEPL Report no. 2, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - "Large Scintillators: Cerenkov Counters for High Energies," HEPL Report no. 9, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - "Nuclear Determinations from Electron Scattering," Physical Review, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - "Inelastic Scattering of 190-MeV Electrons in Beryllium," HEPL Report no. 15, also published in Physical Review, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - "High-Energy Electron Scattering and Nuclear Structure Determinations II," HEPL Report no. 16, also published in Physical Review, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - "Electron Scattering from Hydrogen, Deuterium, and Carbon at 190 MeV," Physical Review, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - "Electron Scattering in Hydrogen and Helium," Physical Review, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - "Scintillations and Luminescence in Unactivated NaI," HEPL Report no. 26, also published in Physical Review, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - "Scattering of 192-MEV Electrons from Deutrium," HEPL report no. 37, also published in Physical Review, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - "Electron Scattering from the Proton," HEPL report no. 42, also published in Physical Review, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - "Electron Scattering and Nuclear Structure," HEPL report no. 86, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - "High-Energy Electron Scattering in Rh, Ta, W, and U," Physical Review, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - "High-Energy Electron Scattering and Nuclear Structure Determinations III. -- carbon-12 nucleus," HEPL Report no. 58, also published in Physical Review, 1955 Sep (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - "Inelastic Electron Scattering from Carbon at 188 MeV," Physical Review, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - "The Structure of Nucleons and Atomic Nuclei Determined by High Energy Electron Scattering," HEPL Report no. 83, also published in Physical Review, 1956 Apr (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - "High-Energy Electron Scattering and the Charge Distribution of Selected Nuclei," HEPL Report bo. 69, also published in Physical Review, 1956 Feb (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - "Elastic Scattering of 188-MEV Electrons from the Proton and the Alpha Particle," HEPL Report no. 74, also published in Physical Review, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - "Nuclear Charge Distribution" (empty folder), 1956 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - "Cerenkov Counters", 1956 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - "Structure of the Proton," CERN Symposium, 1956 Apr (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - "The Atomic Nucleus," HEPL report no. 90, also published in Scientific American, 1956 Jul (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - "Resume of European Trip and of Some Impressions Gained," HEPL report, 1956 Aug (Box 1, Folder 77.1)
  - "Research on Electron Scattering and Nuclear Structure," HEPL report no. 122, 1956 Dec (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - "High Energy Electron Scattering and the Electroids Integration of the Alpha Particle" (empty folder), 1956 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - "New Data on the Structure of the Proton", 1956 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - "Electron Scattering and Nuclear Structure," HEPL report no. 86, Russian translation, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - "Electron Scattering and Nuclear Structure", 1956 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - "Nuclear and Nucleon Scattering of High-Energy Electrons,' HEPL Report no. 126, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - "Form Factor Investigation of the Neutron by High-Energy Electron Scattering", 1957 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - "Inelastic Scattering of 500-MeV Electrons from Li and Li7", 1957 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - "Scattering of 420MeV Electrons from Some Nuclei of the First P-Shell" (empty folder), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - "Form Factor Studies of the Proton at High Energies" (empty folder), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - "Electron Scattering Study of Li6" (empty folder), 1957 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - "Incoherent Electron Scattering from the Nucleons in the Beryllium Carbon and the Magnetic Size of the Neutron," HEPL Report no. 129, also published in Physical Review, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - "Magnetic Form Factor of the Neutron," HEPL Report no. 130, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - "Electromagnetic Structure of the Proton and Neutron," HEPL report no. 133, also published in Review of Modern Physics, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - "Interactions of Electrons with Nuclei and Nucleons," Physical Review, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - "Dimensions et Forces Nucleaires (Elastic Scattering of Electrons)", 1958 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - "Magnetic Form Factor of the Neutron at 600 MeV," HEPL Report no. 139, also published in Physical Review, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - "Structure in the Proton and the Neutron", 1958 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - "High-Energy Electron Scattering from Lithium-6," HEPL Report no. 143, also published in Physical Review, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - "A Sodium Iodide (Tl) Total Absorption Spectrometer for High Energies," HEPL Report no. 137, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - "Study of the Magnetic Form Factor of the Neutron at 600 MeV", 1958 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - "Investigation of the Charge Form Factor of the Proton", 1958 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - "On the Structure of Nucleons", 1959 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - "High-Energy Electron Scattering and the Charge Distribution of Carbon-12 and Oxygen-16," HEPL Report no. 149, also published in Physical Review, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - "Cut-Off Models of the Proton", 1959 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - "Neutron Form Factors from High-Energy Electron Deuteron Scattering", 1959 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - "Shower Detectors", 1959 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - "High Energy Electron Scattering Tables", 1960 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - "Nucleon Structure", 1960 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - "Electron Scattering from the Proton," HEPL Report no. 214, also published in Physical Review Letters, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - "Splitting of the Proton Form Factors and Diffraction in the Proton," HEPL Report no. 215, also published in Physical Review Letters, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - "Splitting of the Proton Form Factors and Diffraction in the Proton", 1960 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - "Some Speculative Remarks on the Dirac and Pauli Form Factors of the Neutron," HEPL Report no. 224, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - "A Two-Spectrometer System for High-Energy Electron-Scattering Studies," HEPL Report no. 221, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - "Remarks on the Use of a Solenoidal Iron Free Spectrometer in High-Energy Electron Physics," HEPL Report no. 222, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - "Dirac and Pauli Form Factors of the Neutron," HEPL report no. 232, also published in Physical Review Letters, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - "Electric and Magnetic Structure of the Proton and Neutron," HEPL Report no. 233, also published in Physical Review Letters, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - "Electron Scattering and Nuclear Structure," HEPL Report no. 86, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - "Principal Methods of Measuring Nuclear Size", 1961 (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - "Shower Detectors," CERN 59-4, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - "Electromagnetic Form Factors of the Proton," HEPL Report no. 243, also published in Physical Review, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - "Recent Results on the Form Factors of the Neutron and on the Structure of Nucleons," HEPL report no. 248, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - "Electromagnetic Structure of Proton and Neutron", 1961 (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - "Preliminary Results on Neutron Form Factors" (empty folder), 1961 (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - "New Results on the Structure of Nucleons", 1961 (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - "New Information about the Electromagnetic Structure of the Neutron", 1961 (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - "Electromagnetic Form Factors of the Proton and Neutron", 1961 (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - "The Free Spirit in the University," City College of New York alumni magazine, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - "The Electron Scattering Method and Its Application to the Structure of Nuclei and Nucleons" (lectures, Argentina and Stockholm), 1961 (Box 2, Folder 126)
  - "Neutron Form Factors and Nucleon Structure," HEPL Report no. 258, also published in Physical Review Letters, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 127)
  - "Structure of Nuclei and Nucleons," Science Magazine, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - "New Results on the Electromagnetic Form Factors of Nucleons," HEPL report no. 271, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - "Neutron Form Factors and Nucleon Models", 1962 (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - "Electron Scattering -- Past and Present", 1962 (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - "New Absolute Cross Sections for Electron Scattering by the Proton", 1962 (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - "Inelastic Electron Scattering from Deuterium", 1962 (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - "Angular Distributions and Bound-Nucleon Form Factors by Electron-Proton Coincidence Det. In Inelastic Electron-Deuteron Scattering," American Physical Society (empty folder), 1962 (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - "Electric and Magnetic Form Factors of the He3 Nucleus" (empty folder), 1962 (Box 2, Folder 135)
  - "Detection of pi Mesons in the Presence of Electrons Using a NaI(Tl) Detector", 1962 (Box 2, Folder 136)
  - "New Determinations of Proton Form Factors", 1962 (Box 2, Folder 137)
  - "Thoughts on the Meaning of Modern Science", 1963 (Box 2, Folder 138)
  - "Electron Scattering and Nuclear and Nucleon Structure" (empty folder), undated (Box 2, Folder 139)
  - "New Experimental Proton Form Factors and Theoretical Fit", 1963 (Box 2, Folder 140)
  - "Structure of the He3 Nucleus," HEPL no. 285, also published in Physical Review, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 141)
  - "Electron Scattering in Tritium and He3," HEPL no. 300, also published in Physical Review Letters, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 142)
  - "Retractable Low Temperature Targets for High Energy Physics Experiments," HEPL Report no. 313, also published in Review of Scientific Instruments, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 143)
  - "Analysis of H3 and He3 Form Factors and the Determination of the Charge Form Factor of the Neutron," HEPL report no. 306, also published in Physical Review Letters, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 144)
  - "Electron Scattering," Yearbook of Science and Technology, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 145)
  - "The Electron Scattering Method and Its Application to the Structure of Nuclei and Nucleons", 1964 (Box 2, Folder 146)